Marco Maida



www.maida.me @ mmaidacs@gmail.com

I have extensive experience in designing and implementing systems that solve complex problems at scale.

I have more than ten years of professional expertise, primarily writing C++, Rust, C, Python, C#, and Coq.

I am currently based in London.

Professional Experience

Since 2022 Software engineer – Robotics and AI. Wayve Ltd

I designed, implemented, and maintained several key systems of the on-board software stack of Wayve's autonomous cars. The software collects frames from different sensors; aligns, packages, and uploads enormous amounts of data, and runs a neural network for real-time inference. (ROS2, Linux Kernel, C++, Rust, Python).

2016-2019 **Software Engineer – Videogames.** 34BigThings

I contributed to five major titles, designing and implementing game infrastructure, AIs, gameplays, and dev tools. I worked on single-player and online-multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Switch, and mobiles. (Unity3D, C# and Unreal Engine, C++)

2015-2016 Software Engineer - Videogames, Simulation Maserati, Teoresi, Choralia

This experience groups two freelance B2B projects. First, I built an educational game for mobiles and browsers. I led the project end-to-end, managing one artist I hired. Second, I collaborated with an engineer and an artist to create a 3D visualization tool used for product presentation. (C#, Javascript)

2013-2016 Software Engineer - Industrial Software. R.O. srl

I designed and maintained a suite of software solutions for glass processing factories. The software tracks orders and minimises the cutting machines' work, product waste, and logistic delays. I started as an individual contributor and later transitioned to managing a team of 4 engineers (C, C++, C#, SOL)

Education and Research

2022 Research Internship

Bloomberg LP

I worked on accelerating SAT solving using GPUs (C++, CUDA).

2019-2022

Max Planck Institute

I worked at the intersection of formal verification and real-time systems. Additionally, I worked on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux systems. I mentored three interns and published three papers. (COQ, C, Rust)

2019-2022 **Master in Computer Science** Technische Universität Kaiserslautern

I specialised in real-time systems, doing a joint master and PhD program.

2016-2019

Bachelor in Computer Science

Università degli studi di Torino

I specialised in computability and formal methods.

Publications

2021

Foundational Response-Time Analysis as Explainable Evidence of Timeliness

Max Planck institute

I developed POET, a tool that yields a formally verified worst-case-scenario timing analysis. I first-authored a

publication at ECRTS2022, winning its outstanding paper award. (https://drops.dagstuhl.de/opus/volltexte/2022/16336/pdf/LIPIcs-ECRTS-2022-19.pdf)

2022

From Intuition to Cog: A Case Study in Verified Response-Time Analysis, FIFO Scheduling Max Planck institute We developed a formally verified response-time analysis for FIFO schedulers, challenging the classic pen-and-

paper approach. (https://people.mpi-sws.org/~kbedarka/rtss22.pdf)

Selected Open-Source Projects

2021

POETThe tool I created as part of my first academic publication. It is the first-ever implementation of a foundational response-time analysis. (https://gitlab.mpi-sws.org/RT-PROOFS/POET)

2020-2022

I was one of the main contributors of PROSA during my stay at MPI-SWS. PROSA is one of the most influential formally-verified frameworks in the real-time systems' community. (https://gitlab.mpi-sws.org/RT-PROOFS/rt-proofs)

2022

Personal

I created a novel 2D scannable code that encodes messages as unique trees. (www.maida.me/treecode)

Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit 2018

34BiaThinas

I developed a Unity3D framework that accelerates the creation of production-ready casual games, paired by a

Python toolkit to execute bulk operations on the games. (www.github.com/340penThings)